<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>JCOC611 Blog</title>
		<description>A blog where I talk about general programming, specific code/projects, and other generally interesting subjects..</description>		
		<link></link>
		<atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Encoding Dynamic with JavaScript in Cassandra</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cassandra.apache.org/&quot;&gt;Cassandra&lt;/a&gt; is a scalable NoSQL database system first developed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://facebook.com&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;. Within its implementation, it includes a query language similar to SQL called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.datastax.com/documentation/cql/3.1/cql/cql_intro_c.html&quot;&gt;CQL&lt;/a&gt;, which can be used for pretty much any data operation. This language uses a data type similar to JSON called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.datastax.com/documentation/cql/3.0/cql/cql_using/use_map_t.html&quot;&gt;maps&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>/web/cassandra-map</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/web/cassandra-map</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Why Geeks should Write</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;I recently started a course at the University of Toronto that requires us to keep a &lt;em&gt;sLOG&lt;/em&gt;, and this happens to be the first required topic we were instructed to write about. The thing is, the topic somehow implies that there is some sort of cultural belief that they &lt;em&gt;shouldn&amp;#8217;t&lt;/em&gt;. I mean, I personally believe that &lt;em&gt;everybody&lt;/em&gt; should write, regardless of where that writing takes place. However, most people imagine Computer Scientists (or programmers in general) as anti-social beings that live in basements and somehow are not interested in communicating with others. The truth is that our field is much more social than most people would think. Since projects can yield visible results in short periods of time, and both code and thoughts can be interchanged effortlessly through the internet, &lt;em&gt;writing&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;reading&lt;/em&gt; blogs is one of the best investments a geek can make in order to gain knowledge and recognition in the field.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>/slog/why-geeks-should-write</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/slog/why-geeks-should-write</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>